turn2us.org.uk 2019-11-16

# Turn2us Privacy Policy - Turn2us

  1. Your privacy

  2. Who we are

  3. How we collect your information

  4. The categories of data we collect

  5. The basis for processing your data and how we use that data

  6. When your personal data may be shared with others

  7. Monitoring of communications

  8. Retention of your data

  9. International transfers

  10. Your rights

  11. Questions and concerns

### 1\. Your Privacy

This Privacy Policy sets out how and why we obtain, use, share and protect your personal information. For these purposes, Turn2us is the Controller of your personal information in accordance with the General Data Protection Regulation and other UK data protection laws. Turn2us may change this Privacy Notice from time to time. 

Back to top of page

### 2. Who we are

Turn2us (the trading name for Elizabeth Finn Care) is a charity registered in England and Wales with registration number 207812; and in Scotland with registration number SC040987), of Hythe House, 200 Shepherds Bush Road, London W6 7NL.

#### Back to top of page

### 3\. How we collect your information

We may collect your personal data in a number of ways, for example:

  * When you communicate with us by post, telephone (including via our Helpline), fax, SMS, email or other forms of electronic communication;
  * When you make a donation to Turn2us or raise money for us. Sometimes when you support us, your information is collected by an organisation working for us (e.g. a professional fundraising agency) but we are responsible for your data at all times;
  * When you attend a Turn2us event or meeting or otherwise provide your details to a Turn2us member of staff, volunteer, trustee or other representative;
  * When you complete a Turn2us survey or questionnaire;
  * From third parties such as independent event organisers, for example the London Marathon or fundraising sites like Just Giving or Virgin Money Giving (where you have indicated that you are happy for them to do so);
  * From third party, social media and public domain sources in respect of tailoring communications for our supporters and fulfilling criteria for our grant making (see below for further information);
  * When you register for an account or enter information on our website, for example when you or a third party working on your behalf use our Benefits Calculator, Grants Search tool or sign up for our newsletter/s;
  * From the information that you or a third party working on your behalf provide when you make a grant application or fill in another Turn2us form yourself or on behalf of any organisation/individual.

Back to top of page

### 4\. The categories of data we collect

We may collect the following categories of personal data about you:

  * Your name and contact information such as address, email address and telephone number (and, on an ongoing basis, any change of address details);
  * Bank or credit card details (in respect of making a donation or receiving a grant);
  * Date of birth, gender, health/disability information and information relating to your relationship and financial status (in respect of eligibility for grants and for the Benefits Calculator/Helpline/Turn2us Connect services we offer);
  * Technical information collected through the use of cookies about your use of our website. For full details, please see our Cookies Policy;
  * Information concerning your engagement with Turn2us, including records of communications between you and us and your attendance at events and meetings organised by Turn2us;
  * Medical information such as dietary requirements where we require this information to provide catering services to you at our events;
  * Your opinion and feedback in relation to any surveys or questionnaires issued by Turn2us that you complete, such as feedback on our charitable services and events; and
  * In respect of our supporters, information from public domain sources to help us to understand what aspects of Turn2us and our work may be of interest to you.

Back to top of page

### 5. The basis for processing your data and how we use that data

#### 1\. Legitimate interests

We may process your personal data because it is necessary for our or a third party's legitimate interests. This will always be weighed against your rights, interests and expectations. Our legitimate interests include the operation of Turn2us in accordance with our charitable objects.  

Examples of where we process personal data in accordance with our legitimate interests include:

  * To correspond with you about our charitable services, including details of events and of our welfare services, that you have requested from us;
  * To process donations and payments, and to ask for further support by post or telephone if you have done so in the past;
  * To provide tailored information/results to you through the Benefits Calculator, Helpline or Turn2us Connect service (unless we are required to obtain your explicit consent, for example in respect of medical information – see below);
  * To evaluate whether you may qualify for a grant (either from Turn2us or from another charity to which we may assist you in applying) and to process and record your grant application, and make any payments as applicable;
  * To inform you of media opportunities, potentially, and of opportunities to write or feature in newsletter and other Turn2us content, and to send you these newsletters and other similar updates from time to time;
  * Processing technical information about your use of our website to ensure that content on our website is presented in the most effective manner;
  * Processing enquiries and complaints;
  * Tailoring our communications to supporters (see further below).
  * Carry out research and analysis, either in house or via a third party, of the services we provide so that we can improve these in future

##### Building profiles of our supporters and targeting communications

We may use profiling and analytical techniques to ensure communications are relevant and timely, and to provide an improved experience for our supporters.  Analysis also allows us to target our resources effectively, which donors consistently tell us is a key priority for them. We do this because it allows us to understand who, how and why people support us and helps us to make appropriate requests to supporters who may be able and willing to give more than they already do. Importantly, it enables us to raise more funds, sooner, and more cost-effectively, than we otherwise would. 

When building a profile,we may analyse giving history, geographic, demographic and other information relating to you in order to better understand your interests and preferences in order to contact you with the most relevant communications. In doing this, we may use additional information from third party sources when it is available. Such information is compiled using publicly available data about you, for example addresses, listed directorships or typical earnings in a given area. Please let us know if you are a supporter and would prefer us not to undertake such profiling. (See Contact details below.)

#### 2\. Legal obligations

We may also process your personal data for our compliance with our legal obligations. In this respect, we may use your personal data to comply with subject access requests of others, tax legislation (including processing Gift Aid claims), safeguarding requirements (for example those required by the Charity Commission), for the prevention and detection of crime, and in order to assist the police and other competent authorities with investigations (including criminal investigations).

#### 3\. Consent

In some circumstances Turn2us may seek your specific consent to process your personal data: for example:

  * If we wish to use your name, likeness or an attributed quote in our newsletter, on our website or in marketing materials or as a case study to demonstrate the impact of our work;
  * Sending marketing communications in relation to appeals, our services, events and resources by, electronic mail and SMS, in respect of which we operate an ‘opt-in’ communications policy;
  * As part of our Benefits Calculator/Turn2us Connect/Helpline/Grants Search/Grant-giving services, where we ask for medical/health information (‘special category data’ for which your explicit consent is required for processing) in order to provide you with the calculations and information you require;
  * When working with charity, public sector or corporate partners where we have a relationship that we believe could help your financial or personal circumstances.

We will normally seek consent when processing your medical information in other contexts, such as dietary requirements for events. At times, the processing of personal data concerning your health may be necessary to protect your vital interests (such as your immediate safety) and it may not be appropriate to seek your consent in such circumstances.

If you have given your consent and you wish to withdraw it, please contact us using the contact details below. Please note that where our processing of your personal data does not rely on your consent, we may not be able to fulfil your request (please see Your Rights section below).

Back to top of page

### 6. When your personal data may be shared with others

For the purposes referred to in this Privacy Notice, and relying on the bases for processing as set out above, we will share your personal data with certain third parties, including:

  * Our volunteers (including visitors), agents and contractors where there is a legitimate reason for their receiving the information;
  * Third parties whom we engage to assist in delivering our services to you;
  * Other charities (when you are making an enquiry/application for a grant to a particular charity or fund through Turn2us’ Grant Search online application process);
  * Our bank, to whom payment details are provided in order to process donations and payments;
  * Our website operator, who may store details such as name and email address (for example in respect of our e-newsletter mailing list);
  * Internal and external auditors;
  * Our professional advisers and/or insurers where it is necessary for us to obtain their advice or assistance;
  * Professionals who assist us in putting together, printing and delivering our newsletter (and other materials) and website content, and our IT support and data storage provider(s);
  * When we are legally required to do so (by a court, government body, law enforcement agency or other authority of competent jurisdiction), for example by the Charity Commission.
  * When carrying out research and analysis in order to improve our services.

We will never share your personal details with third parties for their own marketing purposes.

Back to top of page

### 7. Monitoring of communications

We record calls to our Helpline for training and service delivery purposes so that we can provide you with help and guidance in respect of benefits calculations and grant searches.

Back to top of page

### 8. Retention of your data

We may retain your personal data for as long as it is necessary to deliver our charitable services; and to protect our legal interests (for example where required by relevant authorities or for a reasonable legal limitation period after we have ceased providing grant funding or services); or as otherwise stated to you when your data is collected; or for such period as we reasonably consider appropriate in connection with our relationship with you and/or the organisation you represent/ed; or for record-keeping and archival purposes. 

Back to top of page

### 9. International transfers

As a matter of course, we do not transfer your personal data outside the European Economic Area (EEA) with the exception of organisations that adhere to the Privacy Shield Framework. We may, however, transfer your personal data around the world on an ad hoc basis, for example where this is necessary for interaction with you and you are located outside of the EEA. In such circumstances, we will consider whether any additional measures are required in order to give adequate protection for the information when it is transferred outside of the EEA.

Back to top of page

### 10. Your rights

You have the following rights:

  * To be informed what personal data we hold about you and/or to obtain access to it (i.e. by receiving a copy of it in a permanent form);
  * To require us not to send you direct marketing communications;
  * To require us to correct the personal data we hold about you if it is inaccurate;
  * To require us (in certain circumstances) to erase your personal data;
  * To request that we restrict our data processing activities (and, where our processing is based on your consent, you may withdraw that consent, without affecting the lawfulness of our processing based on consent before its withdrawal);
  * To receive from us the personal data we hold about you which you have provided to us, in a reasonable format specified by you, including for the purpose of you transmitting that personal data to another data controller; and
  * To object, on grounds relating to your particular situation, to any of our particular processing activities where you feel this has a disproportionate impact on your rights.

Please note that the above rights are not absolute and we may be entitled to refuse requests where exceptions apply: for example if we have reason to believe the personal data we hold is accurate or we can show our processing is necessary for a lawful purpose set out in this Privacy Notice.

You can find out more about your rights under data protection legislation at the [Information Commissioner' Office website](https://ico.org.uk/).

Back to top of page

### 11. Questions and concerns

If you have queries or requests, such as unsubscribing or changing your details, please contact

  * By email: [consent@turn2us.org.uk](mailto:%63onsen%74@tu%72n2%75s%2Eo%72g.uk)
  * By telephone: 020 8834 9200
  * By post: Turn2us, Hythe House, 200 Shepherd’s Bush Road, London W6 7NL.

If you have any questions or concerns about how we process your personal data or you wish to exercise any of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) rights set out above, please see the GDPR Requests page.

Back to top of page

Last updated: 6th March 2019
